Wrege, Charles D. Papers 6012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Material on Hugo Munsterbergs early decision making studies. CD Wrege explored the psychological aspects of decision making. It also is marked as including the International Management Institute Papers and the Tuck School theses. Ive temporarily (Box 24)
  - Paper on "Pioneer Documents in MIS A Closer Look" - AIDS 10/25/78, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 76)
  - 1981 "Achieving Social Change Through Scientific Management: Mary Pattison and 'Domestic Engineering': 1909-1916" - Manuscript (Box 24, Folder 77)
  - Midwest Academy of Mgt. Paper 1980, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 78)
  - "The Roots of Shop Management" 1981 (Box 24, Folder 79)
  - 1981 Academy of Management Convention Program with C.D. Wrege Papers (Box 24, Folder 80)
  - Mary Pattison and Scientific Management 1981 (Box 24, Folder 81)
  - Manuscript of Sawyer-Electro Dynamic Light Co. Paper 1983 (Box 24, Folder 82)
  - NE AIDS Paper on "Improving Health Care Through Scientific Management: 1912-1917" 1982 (Box 24, Folder 83)
  - C.D. Wrege, Greenwood, and Mundy - "Hugo Munsterberg's Pioneer Studies of Management Decision Making (1909-1915)" (Box 24, Folder 84)
  - E.W. Sawyer and America's First Incandescent Lighting Company: 1878-1881, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 85)
  - Illustrations for Electro-Dynamic Paper, 1878-1984 (Box 24, Folder 86)
  - "Reappraising Frederick Taylor's Work" 1983 (Paper Submitted to the 1983 Mgt. Hist. Div. of the Academy of Mgt.) (Box 24, Folder 87)
  - Medical Men and Scientific Management: A Forgotten Chapter in Management History, 1982-1983 (Box 24, Folder 88)
  - "The Efficient Management of Hospitals" 1983 AIDS Meeting, 1982-1983 (Box 24, Folder 89)
  - Origins of Small Group Research, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 90)
  - 1986 "Early Management Information Systems in the Northeast" Northeast Business and Economics Association (for November 1986 Conference) (Box 24, Folder 91)
  - Louisville: Organizational Policy and Development 1984 Conference (Box 24, Folder 92)
  - C.D. Wrege, Greenwood, and Hata: "Psychiatry in Industry Before Mayo: Pioneer Work of Jau Don Ball and August Vollmer, 1916-1922" 1988 (Box 24, Folder 93)
  - Origins of "Bookkeeping Under the Taylor System" Manuscript 1983, 1975-1983 (Box 24, Folder 94)
- Manuscripts and copies of CD Wrege Papers and Articles.. (Box 25)
  - Newspaper Items on the Death of Hugo Munsterberg - 12-16-1916 From Evening Transcript Boston (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - The Keppele Hall Papers, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Who Were Elton Mayo's "Many Hands" (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - "The Search for Schmidt" American Cemetery Sept. 1964, pp. 39-40 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - IMI Paper (Business History Conference) March 1987 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - 84 "Before Bales: Early Research in Small Group Behavior: 1923-1930 (Manuscript), 1984 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Wrege, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Hawthorne's Roots, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Paper for Economic and Business Historical Society 1984 (on NCGA) (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Reduced Charts for "Decision Models" Article - MIS, 1909-1923 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Bevan on Hawthorne Article, Reviews 8-1-79, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Couger Article on Systems Analysis 1973 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Paper 1985, "Early Case Writing in the 1920's and The Emergence of The Measurement of Human Relations" Wrege and Greenwood (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript of "Discovering The Real Frederick Taylor" 29 Pages (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Garland Publishing Co. and C.D. Wrege's Dissertation July 12, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Paper: "Medical Men and Scientific Management" (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - 1985 - Paper "A Historian Looks at An Unusual Information System of the 1920's" (Box 25, Folder 17)
    Original document (booklet) and copy
  - Misc. Wrege Papers, 1984-1986 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - The N-File Newsletter, Nov. 1984 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Proceedings of 1990 Conference of the Midwest Management Society (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - The N-File Newsletter, July 1980 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Review of "Parallelism of Knowledge and The Inevitability of Scientific Management for Academy of Management Review" May 1994 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Lance Metz - 1994 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Pergamon Press and The Journal of Management History 2/1/91, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - The Locktender, Summer 1995 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Bolton June 16, 94 - CDW on being Editor of Special Issue on Hawthorne - Jl. Of Mgt. History, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Manuscript Pages of Jl. Of Mgt. History "Management and The Worker: A Dubious Document" p. 1, 2, 1A, 3, 4, 4A, 4AA, 5, 6, 6A, 7A, 7B, 7, 8, 9, 10-18 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Manuscript for Jack Rabin (Jl. Of Mgt. History) on Taylor Talk of Nov. 7, 1907, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - The Inquiry, 1930-1984 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    Original documents, booklets, copies, and transparency
  - Data on Goodwin Watson, George D. Pratt Jr. and The Inquiry (From Richard Peterson 4/17/84), 1928-1977 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Robert Valentine Papers (Copies) From His Daughter - Taylor, 1912-1917 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Data on Valentine from Harvard Class of Reports, 1896-1991 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Southard Data to File 1978 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Hugo Munsterberg Letters with E.B. Titchener 1908-1914 at Cornell Univ. as of 1981 - Munsterberg (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Jau Don Ball Paper - Academy Meeting 1989 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Southard - Ball, 1920 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Robert M. Yerkes and Elmer Southard - Yerkes Papers, Yale University Library, 1876-1956 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Medical Men and Management, 1917-1976 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence with William Gay (on Southard), 1979 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - "Wrege Papers", 1907-1978 (Box 25, Folder 40)
- Manuscripts and copies of CD Wrege Papers and Articles.. (Box 26)
  - Canal History and Cincinnati Historical Society Bulletin, 1976-1992 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Copy of document and book
  - Layout of Conference Dinner of Directors of Taylor Society April 28, 1927 - Taylor Society (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin of Taylor Society, 1921 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Society for Advancement of Mgt. Letter 1942 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Sanford Thompson Letter of 12/29/32 on Alford and His "Hoboes", 1885-1963 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Taylor Society Correspondence, 1921 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Sanford Thompson 1932 and 1938 Letters, 1932-1938 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Soc. For Advancement of Management May 22-23, 1941 (Cooke Talk) Also Letter to Cooke's Butler 1/21/59, 1941-1959 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Boston Members of Taylor Society 1921 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Constitution of Taylor Society, 1921 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Taylor Society Letters - List 1921, 1919-1921 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Letter to William Latham, Wynnewood, PA - 1983 on Taylor Society Records (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Survey by C.D. Wrege of Taylor Society Bulletins in 1920's (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Index to Taylor Society Bulletin 1914-1934 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Guide to Taylor Society Bulletin (From Greenwood), 1914-1934 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - W.H. Leffingwell Letter to S. Thompson June 3, 1933 on Taylor Society Crisis (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Data on Taylor Society - (NY Public Library Card File), 1911-1934 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Thompson and Hopf and Taylor Society 1935 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Scudder, Klyce, and Taylor - Wrege, 1928 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    Original document (copies of documents - book)
  - Early Notes on Article on Taylor and Cooke July 1975 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - 1975 Paper on Cooke's Industrial Mgt. for Academy of Management (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Secret Alliance Paper - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Feiss Data 76, 1922-1976 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - "John W. Starr: Cincinnati's Forgotten Genius" Cinn. Historical Society Bulletin, Summer, 1976, 1845-1976 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Manuscript of "History in Boxes: The Concealed World of Frederick W. Taylor" (41 Typed Pages) 1977 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Wills Paper MS. Academy of Mgt. 77, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Search for Schmidt Paper 1977 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence on Southeast Amer. Institute of Decision Sciences 1977 Paper on Origins of MIS (Rough Copy) - 1977 Paper S.E. AIDS (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Cooke Creates a Classic 78, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - "Using Pioneer Flow Charts to Analyze the Construction of a Hospital" 8/20/79 - AIDS Paper Fall 1979 Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Hospital Mgt. Paper - Academy of Mgt. 1980, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Northeast AIDS Paper on String Control Boards - 1985 (At Corona Typewriter by Percy Brown) (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Keppele Hall Paper 1980 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - 1980 "The Past Helps The Present: The Practical Use of Management History to Improve Information Flow in a Hospital" Mid West Academy, 1980-1984 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - 1980 "The Real Hawthorne" Eastern Academy of Mgt. (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - 1981 - Pioneer Mgt. Info System in Boston - AIDS (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - 1981 "The Map of Management History" Eastern Academy of Management (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Paper on Decision Making Before WWI - Copy of Original Sheets - Also Research by Louis Rabenda, Columbia 1975 - 1981 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Clues to Mgt. History 1981 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - 1981 "Management History Misinterpreted" Eastern Academy of Management (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - 1981 Extracts from Chordal's Letters: Academy of Mgt. (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - Mary Pattinson Paper Academy of Mgt. History Division 1981 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - 1982 - New York City to Columbus, Ohio: How Illumination Tests Conducted from 1914 to 1923 Influence the Hawthorne Studies" Mid West Academy of Mgt. (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - 1982 "The Last Decision" AIDS (Box 26, Folder 44)
  - 1983 "Decisions at Hawthorne" Eastern Academy of Mgt. (Box 26, Folder 45)
  - 1982 "Charting the Hawthorne Studies - Day-By-Day Analysis of Historic Documents Reveals Errors of 'Arm Chair' Critics - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - 1982 "Hugo Munsterberg's Pioneer Studies in Decision Making" Academy of Management Proceedings (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - 1984 "Clues to Management History: Some Unusual Sources" Proceedings, Eastern Academy of Management (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - "Charting The Hawthorne Studies: 'Pay By Day'" C.D. Wrege and J. Cevasco, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - Inquiry Paper MS. (Wrege-Hata), 1921-1930 (Box 26, Folder 50)
  - Economic and Business Historical Society 1984 (Box 26, Folder 51)
  - "Before Bales: Early Research in Small Group Behavior: 1923-1930" 1984 (Box 26, Folder 52)
  - Original Manuscript of Consultants to Mgt. 10/20/85, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 53)
  - Comparisons of Pages of the MS. Of Ind. Mgt. and Principle of Scientific Mgt. (Box 26, Folder 54)
  - Xerox of Handwritten Copy of "Before Mayo: Forgotten Experimenters and Experiments at Hawthorne" 43 Pages Plus Additional Notes (Box 26, Folder 55)
  - 1985 "The Social Sciences Scientific Mgt. and Hawthorne Studies" Southern Mgt. Assoc. (Box 26, Folder 56)
  - 1985 - Announcement of Publication of "American Business History Series" Garland Publishing Co., 1985 - See p.6 on C.D. Wrege Book (Box 26, Folder 57)
  - 1986 - "Achieving Stability in Auto Production" Northeast AIDS (Box 26, Folder 58)
  - 1986 "Consultants to Management" Eastern Academy of Mgt. (Box 26, Folder 59)
  - 1986 "Pioneer Educational Activities of the National Commercial Gas Association" Essays in Economics and Business History (Box 26, Folder 60)
  - Various C.D. Wrege Papers, 1977-1981 (Box 26, Folder 61)
  - C.D. Wrege Papers, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 62)
- Mary B. Gilson and Mrs. Richard A. Feiss Letters and also includes Mrs. Kirbys Will Research for Management Pioneers and the Erie Organization Chart Search. CDW has a lot of correspondence with MB Gilson who worked for Richard Feiss and Mrs. RA. Feis (Box 27)
  - Keppele Hall Report 1916 (File Under Feiss) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Fanny Hall (Wife of Keppele Hall of Joseph and Feiss Co.) 10-13-61, 9-21-61 - Taylor System, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Mary Hennen Feiss, 1917 Paper on "Personal Relationship at ClothCraft" (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Midwest Management Society Paper on Feiss and Southard 1990 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Copies of Barth and Feiss Letters 1919-1928, 1917-1928 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Mary B. Gilson Papers at Wellesley College - 1978 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Feiss Data in Western Reserve Historical Society 1985, 1911-1985 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Letter to Mrs. Richard A. Feiss 1958-59 Plus Replies, 1958-1959 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - To Mrs. R.A. Feiss 11/9/77 on Golden Book (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Material on Richard A. Feiss for "Golden Book" Nov. 9, 1977 (Not Accepted) - R.A. Feiss 1977 for Golden Book (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - 1978 Correspondence with Mrs. Richard A. Feiss (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Mrs. Feiss 1979 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Mrs. Feiss - 1960, 3 Pages (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Copies of Mary B. Gilson and Mrs. Feiss Letters from Mrs. Feiss (Includes C.D. Wrege Letters), 1954-1959 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence with Mary B. Gilson (on Feiss) 1957, 1957-1959 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Mary B. Gilson Letters on Hawthorne and Feiss and British Strike of 1926 - 1957, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Mary B. Gilson Letters on Review of Mgt. and Worker to Elton Mayo 3/14/1940 in Baker Library, Harvard 4/3/58 CDW, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Review of Mgt. and Worker, Mary Gilson, Amer. Jl. Sociology 1940-41, pp.98-101, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Original Letter from Ordway Tead, 3/21/58 on Mary B. Gilson Book, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Gilson Data for Golden Book 11/7/77, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Copies of Letters from Mary B. Gilson to Mrs. Richard A. Feiss 1954-1957 (Obtained from Mrs. Feiss) (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Mary B. Gilson - "Work of the Employment and Service Dept. of the ClothCraft Shops" (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Paper from Manuscript on R.A. Feiss - 1976, 1915-1976 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Feiss Research 1982 - Marge Paradis Research (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Feiss, 1920-1931 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Data on Joseph and Feiss Co. 1914, 1914-1958 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Francis Mitchell Letter to Cooke on Feiss Letter 7-6-1915 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Original Article by M.B. Gilson 1916 on "Home Conditions to Industrial Efficiency" (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Feiss Visitors Book, 1911-1924 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Mary Hennen (Mrs. Richard Feiss) Personal Relationship and Women at ClothCraft Shops, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Mary Hennen Feiss Paper 1919 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Richard A. Feiss Photo 1923 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    Original photo
  - Visitor Record - Joseph and Feiss Co. (1910-1924) Original Now at Cornell (From C.D. Wrege) - R.A. Feiss (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Barth to Feiss - 10/22/23 on Feiss in Boston and Mrs. Feiss, 1923 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - ClothCraft Shops 1924 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    Transparency and copies of original documents
  - Richard Feiss Poem 1925 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - R. Feiss to Cooke - April 12, 1926 (To Be Married, April 15, 1926 in NYC) Feiss (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Moody's Manual of Investments - 1926-1975 on Joseph and Feiss Co. (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Richard Feiss on Manufacturing Laboratories Inc. Stationary - Oct. 24, 1928 (Copies) (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - Mary B. Gilson Letters, 1957-1958 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Records of the Joseph and Feiss Company at Western Reserve Historical Society 1977 (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - Survey of Feiss Letters etc. at Case-Western Reserve Univ. 1986 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Mary Pattison Paper "Domestic Engineering" Paper, 1909-1916 (Box 27, Folder 43)
  - Mary Pattison - Domestic Engineering Data and Colonia Housekeeping Station 1980 (Box 27, Folder 44)
  - Society for Human Engineering Inc., Goldwin Mayer Clifford Cheasley, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 45)
  - Mary Pattison (Colonia, NJ) "Housekeeping Experiment Station" From: Colonia Yesterday Home Mgt. Chapter 15, Also Diantha Ain Letters (Daughter of Mrs. Pattison) 1909, 1909-1981 (Box 27, Folder 46)
  - Experimental Housekeeping Station Outlook - Vol. 102, Sept. 28, 1912 (Box 27, Folder 47)
  - Mary Pattison Research 8/13/85, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 48)
  - Housekeeping Experiments 1911-1913, Mary Pattison, 1911-1981 (Box 27, Folder 49)
  - Mary Pattison - Domestic Engineering Paper by C.D. Wrege, Correspondence with Diantha Ain (Daughter of Pattison) 1981, Letters 1981 (Box 27, Folder 50)
  - Diantha Pattison, Mary Pattison (Mrs. Frank A.) "Efficient Home" in NY Times Personal Name Index, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 51)
    Original documents and copies of photos
  - Articles on The Home from The Outlook Dec. 1911 to Sept. 1912, Use for Home Mgt., 1911-1912 (Box 27, Folder 52)
  - "Drawing of Little Blue House" on Chain O'Hills Road - Colonia 1949, Belonged to Mary Pattison (Box 27, Folder 53)
  - Shelia Inderlied Letters (On Mary Pattison), 1981 (Box 27, Folder 54)
  - Mary Pattison Data for Home Mgt. 1980, 1912-1980 (Box 27, Folder 55)
  - Mary A. Nutting (In Relation to Housekeeping Management) and Gilbreths - Nutting, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 56)
  - Christian Frederick Collection, Harvard - Radcliffe College 2/2/81 Home Management, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 57)
  - Christine Frederick Article on "New Housekeeping" Ladies Home Journal, Sept. 1912 (Box 27, Folder 58)
  - Home Management, 1920 (Box 27, Folder 59)
  - Modern Electric Home Booklet, Cleveland Elec. Co. 1926 With Photographs - Use With Pattison Paper (Box 27, Folder 60)
    Original booklet and photos
  - Mrs. Kirby's Statistical Breakdown of Search for Wills 1977, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 61)
  - Management Wills Paper - 1976 C.D. Wrege and Dora Z. Kirby Working Paper 1976, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 62)
  - Mgt. Wills Paper 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 63)
  - Frank B. Copley, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 64)
    Blue folder with original documents
  - Morris Llewelyn Cooke, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 65)
    Yellow folder with copies and original documents
  - Frank Bunker Gilbreth, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 66)
  - Sanford E. Thompson, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 67)
    Green folder with copies and original documents
  - Carl G. Barth, 1977-1979 (Box 27, Folder 68)
  - Richard A. Feiss, Mrs. Kirby, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 69)
  - Alfred Richard Zahn, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 70)
  - Alexander Hamilton Church (Will Search by Mrs. Kirby), 1978 (Box 27, Folder 71)
    Red folder with copies and original documents
  - Harrington Emerson (Mrs. Kirby), 1978 (Box 27, Folder 72)
  - Mary Parker Follett, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 73)
  - Horace King Hathaway, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 74)
  - Alan Campbell Reiley, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 75)
    Blue folder with copies and original documents
  - Mary Barnett Gilson, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 76)
  - Charles Edward Knoepell, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 77)
  - Dr. Hugo Munsterberg (Muensterberg), 1978 (Box 27, Folder 78)
  - Dr. E.E. Southard, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 79)
  - Robert Valentine, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 80)
  - George Elton Mayo, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 81)
  - Gen. Wm. Crozier, 1855-1942, 1942-1967 (Box 27, Folder 82)
  - Dora Z. Kirby, 10/9/1980 on Search for William H. McElwain Will (Box 27, Folder 83)
  - Professor Erwin H. Schell MIT, Death Data 1965 - Kirby Will (Box 27, Folder 84)
  - Probate Records on Isobel Briggs Putney, Vermont, Friend of Mary Parker Follett 1984 - File Under Kirby Wills - Mary Parker Follett, Isobel Briggs 1984 (Box 27, Folder 85)
  - To Dora Z. Kirby 2/20/83 on Follett and Briggs Wills, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 86)
  - Search for Louise M. Taylor Will, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 87)
  - Search for Wills - F.W. Taylor, Louise Taylor, Mary B. Gilson 1977 (Box 27, Folder 88)
  - Dora Z. Kirby's 1978 Study of Wills of Management Pioneers (Box 27, Folder 89)
  - Wills of Mgt. Pioneers 1980, Mrs. Kirby 1980, 1978-1980 (Box 27, Folder 90)
  - Data on Robert Valentine Will, Mrs. Kirby 1978 (Box 27, Folder 91)
  - Search for Richard A. Feiss Will, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 92)
  - Search for Alexander Hamilton Church Will, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 93)
  - Mary Pattison Will 1946 (Box 27, Folder 94)
  - Death Certificate of John H. Williams, Not Found in NY City, Kirby Will Data, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 95)
  - Search for Morris L. Cooke Will, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 96)
  - Data on Harrington Emerson - Will Search 1978 (Box 27, Folder 97)
  - Mrs. Kirby - Will of Sanford Thompson, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 98)
  - Search for Mary B. Gilson Will, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 99)
  - Harlow Person (Director of Taylor Society) Will 2/27/23, File Under Kirby-Wills, 1923 (Box 27, Folder 100)
  - George H. Henshaw - (Erie RR Chart) On Letter to NY Times Jan. 18, 1891 dated 1/6/91 - Henshaw Died 1/9/91 - Address on Letter 79 State St., Brooklyn 11/15/88, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 101)
  - George H. Henshaw Search, Erie RR Chart, 1856-1983 (Box 27, Folder 102)
  - Data on George H. Henshaw and Erie RR Chart of 1856, 9/27/82 (Box 27, Folder 103)
  - Erie RR Accounting Search and Henry E. Bown, Penn. Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, PA 1983 (Box 27, Folder 104)
  - Data on George Holt Henshaw and Erie RR Chart, Died Jan. 11, 1891, NY Times p.5 (Box 27, Folder 105)
  - George H. Henshaw, Frederick V. Henshaw March 23, 1941, George Herbert Henshaw - Oct. 13, 1937, 1937-1941 (Box 27, Folder 106)
  - George Henshaw and Henry V. Poor (Box 27, Folder 107)
  - Railroad Historical Research 1946 Booklet, Lithographers in NY, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 108)
  - Lithographers in NYC and Erie RR Organization Chart 1855, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 109)
  - Erie RR Chart Search 1983, 1959-1984 (Box 27, Folder 110)
  - Correspondence with Henry Bown of State of PA Archives, Box 1026, Harrisburg, PA 17120 - 1982 on Erie RR (Box 27, Folder 111)
  - Erie RR Organization Chart Search 7/2/84, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 112)
  - Organization Chart of NY and Erie RR, 1856 (Box 27, Folder 113)
  - Erie RR Records at Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, PA - Search for Erie RR Chart 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 27, Folder 114)
  - Data for RR Periodical Research for Erie Chart, 1894 (Box 27, Folder 115)
  - 1869 Chart of New York Central RR (Box 27, Folder 116)
  - Letters to Dir. Of Archives, State of Pennsylvania on Erie Chart 3/9/82, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 117)
  - The Telegraph on The Erie - From Mott, The Story of Erie pp. 415-423, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 118)
  - Daniel Cray McCallum and The Union RR's (from S.H. Holbrook, The Story of American RR's, 1947, pp. 128-130) - Erie Chart Search (Box 27, Folder 119)
- Medical Men and Management on doctors and how they use management in hospitals and surgery. This contains material on Dr. Ernest Coddman who was very interested in the end result system of surgery and Dr. Dickenson who worked with him as well as som (Box 28)
  - Correspondence with Karl Menninger on Dr. Southard 4/23/79, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Data on Gilbreth Letter for Dr. Codman 1914 from JA Brooke (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Dr. E.E. Southard Death Certificate 2/8/20-2/11/20, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Codman and Adair 1916 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Richard J. Wolfe Letters - Wolfe 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Copy of Southard Autobiography - July 27, 1913 (Southard) (Box 28, Folder 6)
    Copy of original document and transparencies
  - Data on Simonds Rolling Machine Co., 1897-1984 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Various Correspondences C.D. Wrege, 1924-1978 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Mark Rose Correspondence 1979, Dodge and Day (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Efficiency in Hospitals 1981 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Last Will and Testament of Jau Don Ball (Names Only 2 Sons: Robert and James Curtis, Wife Magdalena Christina Maisch Ball) (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Dr. Charles Ball on Jau Don Ball 12/12/79, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Letter of June 14, 1979 from Richard Whiting (Univ. of Los Angeles) on Jau Don Ball, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 13)